A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Office of the Arts, Program Files FA640
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Consultant Reports, 1960-1981; VIII
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Philadelphia Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the New York Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Minneapolis Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Los Angeles Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Houston, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Cincinnati Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Chicago Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Boston Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Atlanta Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre), Feb 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts (Symphony, Opera, Ballet, Theatre) Vol. II, Feb 1972 (Box 23)
- Printed Materials and Reports, 1956-1980; IX
  - Fact Sheets, c.1964 (Box 23)
  - Ford Foundation Humanities and the Arts Program, 1963 (Box 23)
  - Arts Management Training -- Research Materials -- Draft Outline, Reports, etc., 1967-1974 (Box 23)
  - Arts Management Training -- Program and Category Lists, 1968-1974 (Box 23)
  - Harvard University, 1969-1974 (Box 23)
  - Ford Foundation Program for University Presses -- Booklet/Brochure, 1956 (Box 23)
  - University Presses Program -- General, 1972 (Box 23)
  - Ford Foundation Booklet -- Ford Foundation Program in Humanities and the Arts, Feb 1959 (Box 24)
  - Ford Foundation Booklet -- William Wallace McPeak - A Memorial Service, 1964 (Box 24)
  - An Enlarged Program in the Arts -- Humanities and the Arts Program Policy Discussion Paper for Board of Trustees Meeting, Mar 1960 (Box 24)
  - National Council of the Arts -- Program Paper and Board of Trustees Draft Resolution (Box 24)
  - Economic and Social Positions of the Artist and His Institutions, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Foster, Donald -- Harvard's Institute of the Arts -- Class Summaries, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Frantisek, Daniel -- French Government Subsidies of Feature Films, Dec 1977 (Box 24)
  - Harewood, the Earl of, 1966-1967 (Box 24)
  - Harrington, Howard, 1971 (Box 24)
  - Kendan, Elizabeth -- American Dance, 1977-1979 (Box 24)
  - Langham, Michael, Apr 1968 (Box 24)
  - Larrabee, Eric, 1975-1979 (Box 24)
  - Markson, Edith, 1964-1973 (Box 24)
  - Martin, John, 1967 (Box 24)
  - Pearlman, Richard, 1970-1971 (Box 24)
  - Peers, Gordon F. -- RISD Painting Department, 1967-1969 (Box 24)
  - Powers, James, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Reinhart, Charles -- Report on Modern Dance, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Ritchie, Andrew -- Art in Museum Storage, 1972-1978 (Box 24)
  - Rueppel, Merrill C., 1970-1972 (Box 24)
  - Schneider, Alan, 1970-1972 (Box 24)
  - Schoenbach, Sol, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Scism, Mack -- Trident Theatre, 1966 (Box 24)
  - Shepherd, Anne -- Reports re: Tyrone Guthrie Theatre and Alley Theatre, 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Sydeman, Hope -- Elgin Theatre Foundation, 1980 (Box 24)
  - Struppeck, Jules -- Sculptural Metal Casting, 1964 (Box 24)
  - Thompson, Ralph -- Reports re: American Classics Series, Translation Project, Theatre and Music, 1964-1975 (Box 24)
  - Trott, Sally -- Kodaly Pilot Project, 1979 (Box 24)
  - Vance, Nina, 1958-1971 (Box 24)
  - Weissenstein, Herbert, 1979 (Box 24)
  - Zeigler, Joseph, 1978-1980 (Box 24)
  - Zeisler, Peter, 1970-1973 (Box 24)
  - Zornow, Edith -- Evaluation of Ford Foundation Program for Film Makers, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Printed Materials (A-O) (1/3), 1958-1970 (Box 24)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Printed Materials (A-O) (2/3), 1958-1970 (Box 24)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Printed Materials (A-O) (3/3), 1958-1970 (Box 24)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Printed Materials (P-Z) (1/2), 1956-1965 (Box 24)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Printed Materials (P-Z) (2/2), 1956-1965 (Box 24)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Forms and Letters (1/2), 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Forms and Letters (2/2), 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Forms and Form Letters -- Grant-in-Aid Programs (1/2), 1958 (Box 24)
  - Forms and Form Letters -- Grant-in-Aid Programs (2/2), 1958 (Box 24)
  - Forms and Form Letters -- Grant-in-Aid Programs, 1959-1960 (Box 24)
- Survey Files, 1964-1976; X
  Includes material related to Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) 07090624 (PA709-624): “FINANCIAL SURVEY OF NONPROFIT PERFORMING GROUPS”.
  - Survey Files -- Symphony Orchestra, 1965-1976; X.1
    - Albany Symphony, 1969-1975 (Box 25)
    - American Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Atlanta Symphony, 1965-1975 (Box 25)
    - Baltimore Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Birmingham Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Boston Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Brooklyn Philharmonia, 1967-1975 (Box 25)
    - Buffalo Philharmonic, 1967-1975 (Box 25)
    - Cedar Rapids Symphony Orchestra, 1965-1975 (Box 25)
    - Chamber Symphony Society of California, 1971-1975 (Box 25)
    - Charlotte Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Chattanooga Symphony, 1969-1975 (Box 25)
    - Chicago Symphony, 1965-1975 (Box 25)
    - Cincinnati Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Clarion Music Society, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Cleveland Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 25)
    - Colorado Springs Symphony, 1967-1975 (Box 25)
    - Colombus Symphony, 1968-1975 (Box 25)
    - Dallas Symphony, 1967-1975 (Box 25)
    - Dayton Symphony, 1968-1975 (Box 25)
    - Des Moines Symphony Association, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Denver Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Detroit Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Duluth Symphony, 1969-1975 (Box 26)
    - El Paso Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Erie Philharmonic, 1971-1975 (Box 26)
    - Evansville Philharmonic, 1971-1975 (Box 26)
    - Florida Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Fort Lauderdale Symphony, 1971-1975 (Box 26)
    - Fort Wayne Philharmonic, 1968-1975 (Box 26)
    - Fort Worth Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Fresno Philharmonic, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Glendale Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Grand Rapids Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Greater Akron Symphony, 1970-1975 (Box 26)
    - Greater Miami Philharmonic, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Hartford Symphony, 1967-1975 (Box 26)
    - Honolulu Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Houston Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Hudson Valley Philharmonic, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Indianapolis Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Jackson Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 26)
    - Jacksonville Symphony, 1969-1975 (Box 26)
    - Kalamazoo Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Kansas City Philharmonic, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Knoxville Symphony, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Little Orchestra Society, 1967-1975 (Box 27)
    - Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Louisville Philharmonic, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Memphis Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Miami Beach Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Minnesota Symphony Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 27)
    - Nashville Symphony Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 27)
    - National Symphony (Washington DC), 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - New Haven Symphony Orchestra, 1965-1975 (Box 27)
    - New York Philharmonic - Symphony, 1967-1975 (Box 27)
    - New Orleans Philharmonic Symphony Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 27)
    - Norfolk Symphony Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 27)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1975 (Box 27)
    - Northeastern Philharmonic, 1974-1975 (Box 27)
    - Oakland Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 27)
    - Oklahoma City Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1975 (Box 27)
    - Omaha Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - Orchestra de Camera, 1974-1975 (Box 28)
    - Oregon Symphony Orchestra, 1965-1975 (Box 28)
    - Pasadena Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - Philadelphia Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 28)
    - Phoenix Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - Portland (Maine) Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1975 (Box 28)
    - Pro Arte Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1975 (Box 28)
    - Rhode Island Philharmonic Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - Richmond Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - Rochester Philharmonic, 1967-1975 (Box 28)
    - Sacramento Symphony Orchestra, 1968-1975 (Box 28)
    - St. Louis Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - St. Paul Civic Philharmonic, 1970-1976 (Box 28)
    - San Antonio Symphony Orchestra, 1969-1975 (Box 28)
    - San Diego Symphony Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 28)
    - San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - San Jose Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1975 (Box 28)
    - Seattle Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 28)
    - Shreveport Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1975 (Box 29)
    - Spokane Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Springfield Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1975 (Box 29)
    - Syracuse Symphony Orchestra, 1968-1975 (Box 29)
    - Toledo Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Tri-City Symphony Orchestra, 1972-1975 (Box 29)
    - Tucson Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Tulsa Philharmonic Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 29)
    - Utah Symphony Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 29)
    - Vermont Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Wichita Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Winson-Salem Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Youngstown Symphony Orchestra, 1967-1975 (Box 29)
  - Survey Files -- Theater, 1965-1976; X.2
    - A Contemporary Theatre Inc, 1975-1976 (Box 29)
    - The Acting Company, 1975 (Box 29)
    - Actors Theatre of Louisville, 1971-1976 (Box 29)
    - Alley Theatre, 1970-1975 (Box 29)
    - American Conservatory Theatre, 1970-1975 (Box 29)
    - American Shakespeare Theater, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Arena Stage, 1966-1975 (Box 29)
    - Asolo State Theater, 1971-1975 (Box 29)
    - Barter Theatre, 1965-1975 (Box 30)
    - Theatre Company of Boston, 1971-1974 (Box 30)
    - Center Stage, 1971-1975 (Box 30)
    - Chelsea Theater Center, 1968-1975 (Box 30)
    - Cincinnati Playhouse in the Park, 1966-1975 (Box 30)
    - Circle in the Square, 1971-1976 (Box 30)
    - Cleveland Playhouse, 1971-1975 (Box 30)
    - Folger Theater Group, 1975 (Box 30)
    - Goodman Theatre, 1971-1975 (Box 30)
    - Guthrie Theater, 1966-1975 (Box 30)
    - Hartford Stage Company, 1966-1975 (Box 30)
    - Indiana Repertory Theater, 1973-1975 (Box 30)
    - Long Wharf Theatre, 1967-1975 (Box 30)
    - Loretto-Hilton Repertory Theatre, 1971-1975 (Box 30)
    - McCarter Theatre Company, 1971-1975 (Box 30)
    - Mark Taper Forum, Center Theatre Group, 1967-1975 (Box 30)
    - Meadow Brook Theatre, Oakland University, 1969-1975 (Box 30)
    - Milwakee Repertory Theater, 1968-1975 (Box 30)
    - New Orleans Repertory Theatre, 1967-1975 (Box 30)
    - New York Shakespeare Festival, 1971-1975 (Box 30)
    - Phoenix Theatre, 1967-1975 (Box 31)
    - Repertory Theater of Lincoln Center, 1971-1975 (Box 31)
    - Seattle Repertory Theatre, 1966-1975 (Box 31)
    - Stage/West, 1968-1975 (Box 31)
    - Trinity Square Repertory Company, 1970-1975 (Box 31)
    - Studio Arena Theatre, 1969-1975 (Box 31)
    - Virginia Museum Theatre, 1975 (Box 31)
    - Washington Theater Club, 1966-1975 (Box 31)
    - Yale Repertory Theatre, 1971-1975 (Box 31)
  - Survey Files -- Modern Dance, 1965-1976; X.3
    - Alvin Ailey City Center Dance Theater, 1971-1975 (Box 31)
    - Merce Cunningham and Dance Company, 1965-1975 (Box 31)
    - Martha Graham Center for Contemporary Dance, 1966-1975 (Box 31)
    - Erick Hawkins Dance Company, 1966-1975 (Box 31)
    - Bella Lewtizky Dance Company, 1971-1975 (Box 31)
    - Jose Greco Foundation for Hispanic Dance, 1973-1975 (Box 31)
    - Jose Limon Dance Foundation Inc., 1975 (Box 31)
    - Murray Louis Dance Company, 1971-1972 (Box 31)
    - Alwin Nikolais Dance Theatre, 1971-1975 (Box 31)
    - Repertory Dance Theatre (Utah), 1971-1975 (Box 31)
    - Twyla Tharp Dance Foundation Inc., 1974-1976 (Box 31)
  - Survey Files -- Miscellaneous Unfiled, 1970-1975; X.4
    - Albuquerque Symphony Orchestra, 1973-1975 (Box 31)
    - American Dance Associates, 1970-1971 (Box 31)
    - American Opera Society, 1971 (Box 31)
    - Bucks County Theatre Company, 1971 (Box 31)
    - Champlain Shakespeare Festival, Arena Theater/University of Vermont, 1971-1972 (Box 31)
    - Charles Playhouse, The, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Survey Files -- Opera, 1965-1976; X.5
    - Baltimore Opera Company, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Opera Company of Boston, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Central City Opera House Association, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Chautauqua Opera Association, 1969-1975 (Box 32)
    - Cincinnati Summer Opera Association, 1967-1975 (Box 32)
    - Connecticut Opera Association, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Dallas Civic Opera Company, 1971-1975 (Box 32)
    - Florentine Opera Company, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Fort Worth Civic Opera Association, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Goldovsky Opera Institute, 1971-1975 (Box 32)
    - Opera Guild of Greater Miami, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Houston Grand Opera Association, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Kansas City Lyric Theater, 1967-1975 (Box 32)
    - Kentucky Opera Association, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Lake George Opera Festival, 1967-1975 (Box 32)
    - Lyric Opera of Chicago, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Memphis Opera Theatre, 1975-1976 (Box 32)
    - Metropolitan Opera Association, 1966-1975 (Box 32)
    - Minnesota Opera Company, 1970-1975 (Box 32)
    - New Orleans Opera House Association, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
    - New York City Opera, 1969-1975 (Box 33)
    - Omaha Opera Company, 1971-1978 (Box 33)
    - Philadelphia Grand Opera Company, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
    - Philadelphia Lyric Opera Company, 1969-1975 (Box 33)
    - Pittsburgh Opera, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
    - Portland Opera Association, 1971-1975 (Box 33)
    - Saint Paul Civic Opera Association, 1965-1975 (Box 33)
    - San Diego Opera, 1971-1975 (Box 33)
    - San Francisco Opera Association, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
    - Santa Fe Opera, 1968-1975 (Box 33)
    - Spring Opera, 1967-1975 (Box 33)
    - Seattle Opera Association, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
    - Western Opera Theater, 1970-1975 (Box 33)
    - Opera Society of Washington, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
  - Survey Files -- Ballet, 1965-1976; X.6
    - American Ballet Theatre, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
    - Ballet West, 1966-1975 (Box 33)
    - Boston Ballet, 1968-1975 (Box 33)
    - City Center Joffrey Ballet, 1967-1975 (Box 33)
    - Hartford Ballet Company, 1972-1975 (Box 33)
    - Houston Ballet, 1966-1975 (Box 34)
    - National Ballet, The, 1966-1975 (Box 34)
    - New York City Ballet, 1971-1976 (Box 34)
    - North Carolina Dance Theatre, 1974-1975 (Box 34)
    - Pennsylvania Ballet, 1965-1975 (Box 34)
    - Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, Inc., 1973-1975 (Box 34)
    - San Francisco Ballet, 1968-1975 (Box 34)
- Subject Files, 1952-1970; XI
  - Active Grants, 1967 (Box 35)
  - Administration -- College and University, 1967 (Box 35)
  - Aging, Grants re:, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Agriculture -- The Farmer, 1970 (Box 35)
  - Annual Report, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Approval by Board, 1962 (Box 35)
  - A.S.A. Papers, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Behavioral Science Grants, 1961 (Box 35)
  - Board Book, 1960 (Box 35)
  - Bricks and Mortar, 1963 (Box 35)
  - Budget Preparation, 1966 (Box 35)
  - Business and Public Administration, 1966 (Box 35)
  - Charitable and Other, 1966 (Box 35)
  - Code Book Material, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Coding Procedures, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Colleges and Universities Report, 1966 (Box 35)
  - Colleges, Private, n.d. (Box 35)
  - Commitments, 1968 (Box 35)
  - Composers, Young, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Conferences, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence, General, 1966 (Box 35)
  - Course Development, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Austria-Burma, 1965 (Box 35)
  - Canada-Hungary, 1967 (Box 35)
  - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Company of the Golden Hind, 1957-1959 (Box 36)
  - Cravath, Swaine and Moore, 1958-1961 (Box 36)
  - Arkansas, University of, 1958-1959 (Box 36)
  - Albert Schweitzer Fellowship of America, 1952-1959 (Box 36)
  - Alexander Turnbull Library, 1956-1959 (Box 36)
  - American Book Publishers Council, 1954-1959 (Box 36)
  - American Council of Learned Societies -- First Grant I, 1954-1957 (Box 36)
  - American Council of Learned Societies -- First Grant II, 1958-1960 (Box 36)
  - American Council of Learned Societies -- Review, Evaluation and Proposals III, Mar-Dec 1960 (Box 36)
  - American Council of Learned Societies -- Worchester Meeting IV, 1956 (Box 36)
  - American Philosophical Association, 1956-1964 (Box 36)
  - Brown University, 1957-1958 (Box 36)
  - Burchard-Stonorov Proposal, 1957-1960 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Conference on Communication in the American Theater, Dec 18-19, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Creative Writers Conference, Feb 21-22, 1958 (Box 36)
    See also Ford Foundation Project file C-638: Program for the creative writer; and Grant file: 05900121 (PA59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS.
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Humanistic Conference [PHOTOS], Mar 14-15, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Economic and Social Positions of the Arts and the Artist, Jan 3-4, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Economic and Social Positions of the Arts and the Artist, Jan 17-18, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Music Conference, May 23-23, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Music Conference, Apr 10-11, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Theater Conference, Apr 21-22, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Theater Conference, Apr 3-4, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Visual Artists Conference, Apr 25-26, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Conferences and Meetings -- Visual Artists Conference, Jun 12-13, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Cooperative Faculty Program -- Program Papers Docket Items, 1956 (Box 37)
  - Cooperative Faculty Program -- General, 1956 (Box 37)
  - Cooperative Faculty Program -- Officer Grants to Tulane and Northwestern, 1956-1957 (Box 37)
  - Cooperative Faculty Program -- Chicago Meeting, Apr 17, 1956 (Box 37)
  - Cooperative Faculty Program -- New Orleans Meeting, Aor 28, 1956 (Box 37)
  - Council on Library Resources -- First Grant, 1956-1960 (Box 37)
  - Council on Library Resources -- Review, Evaluation and Proposals, Apr-Dec 1960 (Box 37)
  - Council on Library Resources -- Folger Shakespeare Library, 1954-1959 (Box 37)
  - Council on Library Resources -- Folger Application (Second), 1955 (Box 37)
  - Council on Library Resources -- Board and Staff, Formation of, 1955-1956 (Box 37)
  - Council on Library Resources -- Planning and Policy Memoranda, Docket, 1955-1956 (Box 37)
  - Council on Library Resources -- Statistics and Charts, 1952 (Box 37)
  - Ernst Morris, 1957 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Ad Hoc Committee on Special Programs, 1957-1959 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Armsey, James W. -- Special Program in Education, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Education Program, 1957-1959 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Henry Ford II, 1957-1958 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Foreign Area Training and Research Program, 1956-1960 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- International Affairs Program, 1954-1960 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- International Training and Research Program, 1958-1960 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Office of Reports, 1957-1961 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Office of Reports -- Humanities and the Arts Brochure, 1957-1959 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- President's Office -- Memoranda to W. McNeil Lowry, 1957-1960 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Secretary's Office -- Memoranda re: Programs, Proposals, Policies, 1957-1960 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Treasurer's Office, 1957-1960 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Trustees -- Briefing Documents, 1954-1955 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Trustees -- Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Trustees -- David, Donald K., 1954-1957 (Box 37)
  - Ford Foundation Programs and Administrative Offices -- Undergraduate Programs Committee, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Grants in Aid Programs -- Miscellaneous, 1957-1961 (Box 38)
  - Grants in Aid Programs -- Administrative Expense Memoranda, 1958-1960 (Box 38)
  - Grants in Aid Programs -- Docket Items and Progress Reports, 1958-1961 (Box 38)
  - Grants in Aid Programs -- Tax Memoranda, 1957-1961 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Administration -- Grant Status Report / Index, 1957-1959 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Administration -- Building Services and Miscellaneous Issues, 1959-1961 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Administration -- Grants, Paintings in Foundation Offices, Miscellaneous, 1956-1958 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Administration -- Grants and Grantee Procedures and Protocol, 1958-1959 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Administration -- Operation Red Tape, 1960 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Administration -- Briefing Agenda -- Including Foundation policies, grant recommendation information and grant follow-up protocols, 1958-1959 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Budget Papers, 1958-1960 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Project File -- Humanistic Scholarship, 1958 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Policy and Planning Papers, Progress Reports leading to HA Program Approval (1/3), 1953-1958 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Policy and Planning Papers, Progress Reports leading to HA Program Approval (2/3), 1953-1958 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Policy and Planning Papers, Progress Reports leading to HA Program Approval (3/3), 1953-1958 (Box 38)
  - Evaluation of American Humanistic Scholarship -- Papers, 1958 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Cleveland University Circle -- Development Foundation, 1957-1958 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- National Council of the Arts (1/2), 1959-1960 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- National Council of the Arts (2/2), 1959-1960 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- National Council of the Arts -- Material on Enlarged Program (1/2), 1959-1960 (Box 38)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- National Council of the Arts -- Material on Enlarged Program (2/2), 1959-1960 (Box 38)
  - Ideas -- Miscellaneous, 1959-1960 (Box 38)
  - Ideas -- Literature, 1959 (Box 38)
  - Ideas -- Theater, 1959 (Box 38)
  - Ideas -- Visual Arts, 1959 (Box 38)
  - Ideas -- Architecture -- List of Contacts, 1959 (Box 38)
  - International Comparative Literature Association, 1956-1960 (Box 38)
  - Lowry, W. McNeil -- European Trip, 1958 (Box 39)
  - Marcus, Stanley, 1959 (Box 39)
  - Margo Jones Theatre, 1959 (Box 39)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology -- Electronic Music, 1958 (Box 39)
  - National Music Council -- General, 1958 (Box 39)
  - National Guild of Community Music Schools, 1960 (Box 39)
  - National Music Council -- Gid Waldrop -- Field Representative Correspondence, 1960 (Box 39)
  - Newcomb College, 1958 (Box 39)